<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item version="1.00">
<basic id="2793">
<itemtype>xnpdata</itemtype>
<titles><title>Experimental data showing the effect of DC extracellular electric fields on neuronal membrane polarization in rat hippocampal slices using fast voltage-sensitive dye imaging technique</title>
</titles>
<contributor uname='admin'>DBPF Administrator 1(admin)</contributor>
<keywords><keyword>NG-Data</keyword>
</keywords>
<description>Abstract / Acknowledgment --- In brains, elecrtic field with substantial gradient is generated by ativities of the brain cells, and it is conceivable that the electic fields modulate neuronal activities. To investigate the effect of DC extracellular electric fields on neuronal membrane polarization, we stained rat hippocampal brain slice preparations with fast voltage-sensitive dye and optically recorded the induced change in membrane potentials. We found that while the somatic regions show mono-phasic polarization with slow timeconstant, a biphasic polarization was observed in the apical dendritic regions. We reported the study in the following paper: M.Bikson, M.Inoue, H. Akiyama, J.K. Deans, J.E. Fox, H.Miyakawa, J.G.R. Jefferys J. Physiol., 557,175-190 (2004) PMID: 14978199 Effects of uniform extracellular DC electric fields on excitability in rat hippocampal slices in vitro. Here we provide raw experimenatal data we recorded in the study. The data were those used to prepare Figure 10 of the paper. Affiliation / E-mail --- Laboratory of Cellular Neurobiology, School of Life Sciences, Tokyo University of Pharmacy and Life Sciences, Hachioji, Tokyo 192-0392, Japan (correspondence:inou@ls.toyaku.ac.jp)</description>
<doi>NGP801</doi>
<last_update_date>2009-10-23T03:33:20Z</last_update_date>
<creation_date>2009-10-23T02:10:30Z</creation_date>
<publication_year>2006</publication_year>
<publication_month>9</publication_month>
<publication_mday>12</publication_mday>
<lang>eng</lang>
<url>https://dynamicbrain.neuroinf.jp/modules/xoonips/detail.php?item_id=2793</url>
<changelogs>
<changelog date='2009-10-23T03:33:20Z'>コメント を変更</changelog>
<changelog date='2009-10-23T03:32:37Z'>コメント を変更</changelog>
<changelog date='2009-10-23T03:30:36Z'>プレビュー, Rights を変更</changelog>
</changelogs>
<index></index>
</basic>
<detail id="2793" version="1.03">
<data_type>other</data_type>
<experimenters><experimenter>H. Akiyama</experimenter><experimenter>H.Miyakawa</experimenter><experimenter>M.Inoue</experimenter></experimenters>
<rights>All rights reserved.

</rights>
<readme>The file can be opened using the Origin (OriginLab Corporation, One Roundhouse Plaza, Northampton, MA 01060 USA, http://www.OriginLab.com).

Data in the Data1BasaltoA window were used to draw the left panel of Fig.10B.
Data in the Data1BasaltoA window are plotted in the Graph1 window.
Labels of the trace correspond to the label of the data column.

Data in the Data2Apicalto window were used to draw the right panel of Fig.10B.
Data in the Data2Apicalto window are plotted in the Graph2 window.
Labels of the trace correspond to the label of the data column.

column A : time in msec
column B : timing of the extra DC electric field stimulation (40 mV/mm)
column C : releative change of dye signal recorded in str.ori 110 micron from the cell layer
.
.
column J : releative change of dye signal recorded in str.rad 275 micron from the cell layer

REFERENCE
1)M.Bikson, M.Inoue, H. Akiyama, J.K. Deans, J.E. Fox, H.Miyakawa, J.G.R. JefferysEffects of uniform extracellular DC electric fields on excitability in rat hippocampal slices in vitro. J. Physiol., 557,175-190 (2004) PMID: 14978199</readme>
<use_cc>0</use_cc>
<cc_commercial_use>1</cc_commercial_use>
<cc_modification>2</cc_modification>
<attachment_dl_limit>1</attachment_dl_limit>
<attachment_dl_notify>1</attachment_dl_notify>
</detail>
</item>
