<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item version="1.00">
<basic id="3463">
<itemtype>xnppaper</itemtype>
<titles><title>Contributions of intrinsic and synaptic activities to the generation of neuronal discharges in in vitro hippocampus</title>
</titles>
<contributor uname='admin'>DBPF Administrator 1(admin)</contributor>
<keywords><keyword>neuron-glia</keyword>
</keywords>
<description></description>
<doi>1131</doi>
<last_update_date>2010-03-27T10:09:22Z</last_update_date>
<creation_date>2010-03-27T10:09:22Z</creation_date>
<publication_year>2000</publication_year>
<publication_month>0</publication_month>
<publication_mday>0</publication_mday>
<lang>eng</lang>
<url>https://dynamicbrain.neuroinf.jp/modules/xoonips/detail.php?item_id=3463</url>
<changelogs>
</changelogs>
<index></index>
</basic>
<detail id="3463" version="1.02">
<authors><author>Ivan Cohen</author><author>Richard Miles</author></authors>
<journal>Journal of Physiology</journal>
<volume>524</volume>
<number>2</number>
<page>485-502</page>
<abstract>1. Extracellular and intracellular records were made from guinea-pig hippocampal slices to<br />examine the contributions of intrinsic cellular properties and synaptic events to the<br />generation of neuronal activity. Extracellular signals were filtered to pass action potentials,<br />which could be detected within a distance of about 80 ìm from a discharging cell.<br />2. Spontaneous action potentials were invariably detected in records from the stratum<br />pyramidale of CA3 region. Blocking excitatory synaptic transmission with NBQX and APV<br />reduced their frequency by 23 ± 35 %. Suppressing synaptic inhibition, while excitation was<br />already blocked, increased the rate of spike discharge to 177 ± 71% of its control value.<br />3. Most action potentials recorded intracellularly from CA3 pyramidal cells were initiated in<br />the absence of a detectable synaptic event. In contrast, most action potentials generated by<br />inhibitory cells located close to stratum pyramidale were preceded by an EPSP.<br />4. In 31 simultaneous recordings, intracellular pyramidal cell action potentials appeared<br />consistently to initiate extracellular spikes with a mean latency of 2·2 ± 1·0 ms. Single<br />inhibitory cell action potentials could initiate a reduction in the frequency of extracellular<br />spikes of duration 10—30 ms.<br />5. Some identified extracellular spikes (n = 9) consistently preceded intracellularly recorded<br />IPSPs. IPSPs were initiated monosynaptically with latencies of 0·9—1·5 ms. In reciprocal<br />interactions, single pyramidal cell action potentials could trigger the discharge of an<br />identified unit that in turn appeared to initiate an IPSP in the same pyramidal cell.<br />6. These data suggest that intrinsic cellular mechanisms underly much of the spontaneous<br />activity of pyramidal cells of the CA3 region of the hippocampus in vitro. Both synaptic<br />inhibition and a strong excitation of inhibitory cells by pyramidal cells act to reduce<br />population activity.</abstract>
<pubmed_id></pubmed_id>
</detail>
</item>
