<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item version="1.00">
<basic id="4373">
<itemtype>xnppaper</itemtype>
<titles><title>Involvement of inositol-1,4,5-trisphosphate receptors in the bidirectional synaptic plasticity induced in hippocampal CA1 neurons by 1–10 Hz low-frequency stimulation.</title>
</titles>
<contributor uname='sfujii'>[en]Satoshi Fujii[/en][ja]藤井 聡[/ja](sfujii)</contributor>
<keywords><keyword>frequency</keyword>
<keyword>synaptic plasticity</keyword>
<keyword>hippocampus</keyword>
</keywords>
<description>We suggest that activation of protein kinase C or inositol-1,4,5-trisphosphate receptors, both coupled to group 1 mGluRs, is involved in the bidirectional synaptic plasticity induced in hippocampal CA1 neurons by 1-10 Hz LFS.</description>
<doi>B01G2</doi>
<last_update_date>2010-12-06T05:56:02Z</last_update_date>
<creation_date>2010-11-22T09:19:54Z</creation_date>
<publication_year>2010</publication_year>
<publication_month>0</publication_month>
<publication_mday>0</publication_mday>
<lang>eng</lang>
<url>https://dynamicbrain.neuroinf.jp/modules/xoonips/detail.php?item_id=4373</url>
<changelogs>
<changelog date='2010-12-06T05:56:02Z'>インデックス を変更</changelog>
</changelogs>
<index></index>
</basic>
<detail id="4373" version="1.02">
<authors><author>SSatoshi Fujii, Yoshihiko Yamazaki, Yoichiro Kuroda and Katsuhiko Mikoshiba§</author></authors>
<journal>Neuroscience</journal>
<volume>168</volume>
<number></number>
<page>346-358</page>
<abstract>In the present study, both potentiation and depression of the synaptic response were induced in hippocampal CA1 neurons by systematically varying the frequency of low frequency afferent stimulation (LFS) between 0.5-25 Hz and the pulse number between 40-1000. The input-response relationship for CA1 synapses showed that LFS at a higher frequency or with a smaller pulse number increased the magnitude of potentiation of the synaptic response by increasing the contribution of N-methyl-D-aspartate receptors (NMDARs) and metabotropic glutamate receptors (mGluRs) to induction of potentiation. One possible mechanism for this bidirectional plasticity was that specific patterns of LFS differentially activate a uniform receptor population in producing depression or potentiation of synaptic responses. However, a pharmacological study indicated that, despite their opposite effects, both the synaptic depression induced by LFS at 1 Hz and the synaptic potentiation induced by LFS at 10 Hz were triggered by co-activation of NMDARs and mGluRs at CA1 synapses.</abstract>
<pubmed_id></pubmed_id>
</detail>
</item>
