<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item version="1.00">
<basic id="4564">
<itemtype>xnppaper</itemtype>
<titles><title>the rolo of the hippocampus in solving the morris water maze</title>
</titles>
<contributor uname='dbpf-office1'>DBPF-Office1(dbpf-office1)</contributor>
<keywords></keywords>
<description></description>
<doi></doi>
<last_update_date>2011-02-03T01:14:21Z</last_update_date>
<creation_date>2011-02-03T01:14:21Z</creation_date>
<publication_year>1998</publication_year>
<publication_month>0</publication_month>
<publication_mday>0</publication_mday>
<lang>eng</lang>
<url>https://dynamicbrain.neuroinf.jp/modules/xoonips/detail.php?item_id=4564</url>
<changelogs>
</changelogs>
<index></index>
</basic>
<detail id="4564" version="1.02">
<authors><author>A. David Redish</author><author>David S. Touretzky</author></authors>
<journal>Neural Computation</journal>
<volume>10</volume>
<number></number>
<page>73-111</page>
<abstract>We suggest that the hippocampus plays two roles that allow rodents to<br />solve the hidden-platformwatermaze: self-localization and route replay.<br />When an animal explores an environment such as the water maze, the<br />combination of place ﬁelds and correlational (Hebbian) long-termpotentiation produces a weight matrix in the CA3 recurrent collaterals such<br />that cells with overlapping place ﬁelds are more strongly interconnected<br />than cells with nonoverlapping ﬁelds.When combined with global inhibition, this forms an attractor with coherent representations of position<br />as stable states. When biased by local view information, this allows the<br />animal to determine its position relative to the goalwhen it returns to the<br />environment.We call this self-localization.<br />When an animal traces speciﬁc routes within an environment, the<br />weights in the CA3 recurrent collaterals become asymmetric. We show<br />that this stores these routes in the recurrent collaterals. When primed<br />with noise in the absence of sensory input, a coherent representation of<br />position still forms in the CA3 population, but then that representation<br />drifts, retracing a route.<br />We show that these two mechanisms can coexist and form a basis for<br />memory consolidation, explaining the anterograde andlimitedretrograde<br />amnesia seen following hippocampal lesions.</abstract>
<pubmed_id></pubmed_id>
</detail>
</item>
