<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item version="1.00">
<basic id="4754">
<itemtype>xnppaper</itemtype>
<titles><title>Stratum lacunosum-moleculare interneurons of hippocampal CA1 region. II. Intrasomatic and intradendritic recordings of local circuit synaptic interactions.</title>
</titles>
<contributor uname='dbpf-office1'>DBPF-Office1(dbpf-office1)</contributor>
<keywords><keyword>Animals</keyword>
<keyword>Electrophysiology</keyword>
<keyword>Evoked Potentials</keyword>
<keyword>Guinea Pigs</keyword>
<keyword>Hippocampus</keyword>
<keyword>cytology</keyword>
<keyword>Pyramidal Tracts</keyword>
<keyword>cytology</keyword>
<keyword>Synapses</keyword>
<keyword>cytology</keyword>
</keywords>
<description></description>
<doi></doi>
<last_update_date>2011-04-28T03:34:05Z</last_update_date>
<creation_date>2011-04-28T03:34:05Z</creation_date>
<publication_year>1988</publication_year>
<publication_month>0</publication_month>
<publication_mday>0</publication_mday>
<lang>eng</lang>
<url>https://dynamicbrain.neuroinf.jp/modules/xoonips/detail.php?item_id=4754</url>
<changelogs>
</changelogs>
<index></index>
</basic>
<detail id="4754" version="1.02">
<authors><author>Lacaille JC</author><author>Schwartzkroin PA</author></authors>
<journal>The Journal of neuroscience : the official journal of the Society for Neuroscience</journal>
<volume>8</volume>
<number>4</number>
<page>1411-24</page>
<abstract>Simultaneous intracellular recordings were obtained from stratum lacunosum-moleculare (L-M) interneurons and CA1 cells, and their local circuit synaptic interactions were examined. Synaptic interactions with pyramidal cells were evaluated in both intrasomatic and intradendritic pyramidal cell recordings. Stimulation of L-M interneurons evoked small-amplitude IPSPs in 21% of intrasomatic (9/42 cell pairs) and in 26% of intradendritic (11/43) pyramidal cell recordings. The IPSP mean peak amplitude was 0.91 mV for intrasomatic and 0.67 mV for intradendritic recordings. IPSPs had slow onset and decay (approximately 80-90 msec), decreased in amplitude with membrane hyperpolarization, and were not associated with any apparent change in input resistance. No physiologic evidence of synaptic connections was found from pyramidal cells to L-M interneurons. Inhibitory synaptic interactions were also seen between L-M interneurons and stratum pyramidale interneurons (2 of 4 cell pairs). The IPSPs recorded in pyramidale interneurons were similar to the IPSPs recorded in pyramidal cells. During simultaneous recordings, L-M interneurons were activated at a shorter latency, i.e., in a feedforward manner with respect to pyramidal cells. Thus, L-M interneurons may mediate feedforward inhibition of CA1 pyramidal cells. The L-M interneuron-evoked IPSPs in pyramidal cells share some characteristics of the late IPSP recorded in CA1 pyramidal cells and may therefore contribute to this component of the IPSP.</abstract>
<pubmed_id>3357024</pubmed_id>
</detail>
</item>
