<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item version="1.00">
<basic id="4784">
<itemtype>xnppaper</itemtype>
<titles><title>Ionic mechanisms of cholinergic excitation in mammalian hippocampal pyramidal cells.</title>
</titles>
<contributor uname='dbpf-office1'>DBPF-Office1(dbpf-office1)</contributor>
<keywords><keyword>Acetylcholine</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Animals</keyword>
<keyword>Barium</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Calcium</keyword>
<keyword>metabolism</keyword>
<keyword>Cholinergic Fibers</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Culture Techniques</keyword>
<keyword>Guinea Pigs</keyword>
<keyword>Hippocampus</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Ion Channels</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Manganese</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Membrane Potentials</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>Neurons</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Potassium</keyword>
<keyword>metabolism</keyword>
<keyword>Receptors</keyword>
<keyword>Muscarinic</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Sodium</keyword>
<keyword>metabolism</keyword>
<keyword>Synapses</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Synaptic Transmission</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>Tetrodotoxin</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
</keywords>
<description></description>
<doi></doi>
<last_update_date>2011-04-28T04:48:52Z</last_update_date>
<creation_date>2011-04-28T04:48:52Z</creation_date>
<publication_year>1982</publication_year>
<publication_month>0</publication_month>
<publication_mday>0</publication_mday>
<lang>eng</lang>
<url>https://dynamicbrain.neuroinf.jp/modules/xoonips/detail.php?item_id=4784</url>
<changelogs>
</changelogs>
<index></index>
</basic>
<detail id="4784" version="1.02">
<authors><author>Benardo LS</author><author>Prince DA</author></authors>
<journal>Brain research</journal>
<volume>249</volume>
<number>2</number>
<page>333-44</page>
<abstract>Intracellular recordings from CA1 hippocampal pyramidal neurons were obtained using the in vitro hippocampal slice preparation. Responses to ACh were monitored in the presence of blockers of voltage-dependent conductances including Mn2+, TTX and Ba2+. When Mn2+ was used to block voltage-dependent Ca conductance and possible indirect presynaptic cholinergic actions, ACh still induced a significant voltage-sensitive increase in apparent input resistance (Ra) (29%), but only an insignificant depolarization of membrane potential (Vm). When both voltage-dependent Ca and Na conductances were blocked by application of Mn2+ and TTX, respectively, ACh produced voltage-dependent increases in Ra (31%) without significant depolarization. In solutions containing TTX alone, ACh produced voltage-sensitive increases in Ra (32%) as well as a significant depolarization (6.2 +/- 3.1 mV (S.D.)). ACh transiently blocked the conductance increase which followed presumed Ca spikes, suggesting an action on the Ca-activated K-dependent conductance. The effects of Ba2+ application (100-200 microM) on Ra mimicked those of ACh. When ACh was applied to neurons in the presence of Ba2+, Ra remained unchanged, although Vm depolarization of 5-15 mV was still seen. The data indicate that ACh decreases both a voltage-dependent K conductance (distinct from that of the delayed rectifier) and a Ca-activated K conductance. Muscarinic cholinergic depolarization occurs as a result of blockade of K conductance, and is mediated by voltage-dependent Ca and Na conductances, and perhaps by presynaptic actions.</abstract>
<pubmed_id>6291716</pubmed_id>
</detail>
</item>
