<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item version="1.00">
<basic id="5963">
<itemtype>xnppaper</itemtype>
<titles><title>Long-term potentiation and long-term depression in hippocampal CA1 neurons of mice lacking the IP(3) type 1 receptor.</title>
</titles>
<contributor uname='dbpf-office3'>DBPF-Office3(dbpf-office3)</contributor>
<keywords><keyword>Action Potentials</keyword>
<keyword>genetics</keyword>
<keyword>Animals</keyword>
<keyword>Calcium Channels</keyword>
<keyword>deficiency</keyword>
<keyword>genetics</keyword>
<keyword>Calcium Signaling</keyword>
<keyword>genetics</keyword>
<keyword>Electric Stimulation</keyword>
<keyword>Excitatory Postsynaptic Potentials</keyword>
<keyword>genetics</keyword>
<keyword>Hippocampus</keyword>
<keyword>metabolism</keyword>
<keyword>physiopathology</keyword>
<keyword>Inositol 1</keyword>
<keyword>4</keyword>
<keyword>5-Trisphosphate Receptors</keyword>
<keyword>Long-Term Potentiation</keyword>
<keyword>genetics</keyword>
<keyword>Long-Term Synaptic Depression</keyword>
<keyword>genetics</keyword>
<keyword>Mice</keyword>
<keyword>Mice</keyword>
<keyword>Knockout</keyword>
<keyword>Pyramidal Cells</keyword>
<keyword>metabolism</keyword>
<keyword>physiopathology</keyword>
<keyword>Receptors</keyword>
<keyword>Cytoplasmic and Nuclear</keyword>
<keyword>deficiency</keyword>
<keyword>genetics</keyword>
<keyword>Receptors</keyword>
<keyword>N-Methyl-D-Aspartate</keyword>
<keyword>metabolism</keyword>
<keyword>Synaptic Transmission</keyword>
<keyword>genetics</keyword>
</keywords>
<description></description>
<doi></doi>
<last_update_date>2012-01-25T05:19:32Z</last_update_date>
<creation_date>2012-01-25T05:19:32Z</creation_date>
<publication_year>2003</publication_year>
<publication_month>0</publication_month>
<publication_mday>0</publication_mday>
<lang>eng</lang>
<url>https://dynamicbrain.neuroinf.jp/modules/xoonips/detail.php?item_id=5963</url>
<changelogs>
</changelogs>
<index></index>
</basic>
<detail id="5963" version="1.02">
<authors><author>Nagase T</author><author>Ito KI</author><author>Kato K</author><author>Kaneko K</author><author>Kohda K</author><author>Matsumoto M</author><author>Hoshino A</author><author>Inoue T</author><author>Fujii S</author><author>Kato H</author><author>Mikoshiba K</author></authors>
<journal>Neuroscience</journal>
<volume>117</volume>
<number>4</number>
<page>821-30</page>
<abstract>To investigate the role in synaptic plasticity of Ca(2+) released from intracellular Ca(2+) stores, mice lacking the inositol 1,4,5-trisphosphate type 1 receptor were developed and the physiological properties, long-term potentiation, and long-term depression of their hippocampal CA1 neurons were examined. There were no significant differences in basic synaptic functions, such as membrane properties and the input/output relationship, between homozygote mutant and wild-type mice. Enhanced paired-pulse facilitation at interpulse intervals of less than 60 ms and enhanced post-tetanic potentiation were observed in the mutant mice, suggesting that the presynaptic mechanism was altered by the absence of the inositol 1,4,5-trisphosphate type 1 receptor. Long-term potentiation in the field-excitatory postsynaptic potentials induced by tetanus (100 Hz, 1 s) and the excitatory postsynaptic currents induced by paired stimulation in hippocampal CA1 pyramidal neurons under whole-cell clamp conditions were significantly greater in mutant mice than in wild-type mice. Homosynaptic long-term depression of CA1 synaptic responses induced by low-frequency stimulation (1 Hz, 500 pulses) was not significantly different, but heterosynaptic depression of the non-associated pathway induced by tetanus was blocked in the mutant mice. Both long-term potentiation and long-term depression in mutant mice were completely dependent on N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor activity. To rule out the possibility of an effect compensating for the lack of the inositol 1,4,5-trisphosphate type 1 receptor occurring during development, an anti-inositol 1,4,5-trisphosphate type 1 receptor monoclonal antibody that blocks receptor function was diffused into the wild-type cell through a patch pipette, and the effect of acute block of inositol 1,4,5-trisphosphate type 1 receptor on long-term potentiation was examined. Significant enhancement of long-term potentiation was observed compared with after control immunoglobulin G injection, suggesting that developmental redundancy was not responsible for the increase in long-term potentiation amplitude observed in the mutant mouse. The properties of channels that could be involved in long-term potentiation induction were examined using whole-cell recording. N-methyl-D-aspartate currents were significantly larger in mutant mice than in wild-type mice only between holding potentials of -60 and -80 mV. We conclude that inositol 1,4,5-trisphosphate type 1 receptor activity is not essential for the induction of synaptic plasticity in hippocampal CA1 neurons, but appears to negatively regulate long-term potentiation induction by mild modulation of channel activities.</abstract>
<pubmed_id>12654335</pubmed_id>
</detail>
</item>
