<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item version="1.00">
<basic id="7209">
<itemtype>xnppaper</itemtype>
<titles><title>Induction of long-term potentiation at hippocampal mossy-fiber synapses follows a Hebbian rule.</title>
</titles>
<contributor uname='admin'>DBPF Administrator 1(admin)</contributor>
<keywords><keyword>Animals</keyword>
<keyword>Electric Stimulation</keyword>
<keyword>methods</keyword>
<keyword>Electrophysiology</keyword>
<keyword>Hippocampus</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Male</keyword>
<keyword>Membrane Potentials</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Models</keyword>
<keyword>Neurological</keyword>
<keyword>Rats</keyword>
<keyword>Synapses</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Time Factors</keyword>
</keywords>
<description></description>
<doi></doi>
<last_update_date>2013-02-27T07:56:46Z</last_update_date>
<creation_date>2013-02-27T07:56:46Z</creation_date>
<publication_year>1990</publication_year>
<publication_month>0</publication_month>
<publication_mday>0</publication_mday>
<lang>eng</lang>
<url>https://dynamicbrain.neuroinf.jp/modules/xoonips/detail.php?item_id=7209</url>
<changelogs>
</changelogs>
<index></index>
</basic>
<detail id="7209" version="1.02">
<authors><author>Jaffe D</author><author>Johnston D</author></authors>
<journal>Journal of neurophysiology</journal>
<volume>64</volume>
<number>3</number>
<page>948-60</page>
<abstract>1. The induction of long-term potentiation (LTP) at hippocampal mossy-fiber synapses requires an increase in postsynaptic [Ca2+]i but is independent of N-methyl-D-aspartate (NMDA) receptor activation. Voltage-gated Ca2+ channels have been proposed as one alternative source for raising [Ca2+]i during the induction of LTP. We tested the hypothesis that voltage-gated Ca2+ channel activation could mediate the induction of LTP by examining whether 1) the induction of mossy-fiber LTP was dependent on postsynaptic depolarization and 2) depolarization alone, of a magnitude presumably capable of activating Ca2+ channels, was sufficient to induce LTP. 2. Intracellular recordings were made from rat CA3 pyramidal cells in the hippocampal slice preparation under both current- and voltage-clamp conditions. Mossy-fiber postsynaptic potentials and currents were recorded before and after high-frequency stimulation (HFS) in the presence of 20-50 microM D-2-amino-5-phosphonovaleric acid (D-APV), an NMDA-receptor antagonist. 3. Voltage clamping of CA3 neurons between -80 and -100 mV during HFS reversibly blocked the induction of mossy-fiber LTP. Conversely, HFS paired with depolarizing-current steps under current clamp increased the magnitude of LTP compared with controls. These results indicate that mossy-fiber LTP is dependent on postsynaptic depolarization, and presynaptic activation alone was not sufficient to induce mossy-fiber LTP. 4. Depolarizing-current injections, which presumably depolarized CA3 cells to potentials sufficient to activate voltage-gated Ca2+ channels, had no effect on mossy-fiber synaptic responses. These results suggest that synaptic activation, in addition to postsynaptic depolarization, is required for the induction of mossy-fiber LTP. 5. Single mossy-fiber afferent volleys were also paired with depolarizing-current pulses. In the presence of APV, pairing of single-mossy-fiber excitatory postsynaptic potentials (EPSPs) with postsynaptic depolarization did not potentiate synaptic responses, suggesting that some form of HFS is also required for mossy-fiber LTP. In the absence of APV, however, the contamination of mossy-fiber synaptic responses by CA3-recurrent inputs resulted in some potentiation. 6. These results suggest that the induction of mossy-fiber LTP is dependent on both pre- and postsynaptic activity and thus follows a Hebbian rule for synaptic modification. In contrast to that demonstrated at Schaffer-collateral-commissural synapses, however, the induction of mossy-fiber LTP may require HFS in addition to postsynaptic depolarization.(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 400 WORDS)</abstract>
<pubmed_id>2230936</pubmed_id>
</detail>
</item>
