<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item version="1.00">
<basic id="7214">
<itemtype>xnppaper</itemtype>
<titles><title>Interferon-alpha inhibits long-term potentiation and unmasks a long-term depression in the rat hippocampus.</title>
</titles>
<contributor uname='admin'>DBPF Administrator 1(admin)</contributor>
<keywords><keyword>2-Amino-5-phosphonovalerate</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Animals</keyword>
<keyword>Enzyme Inhibitors</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Excitatory Amino Acid Agonists</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Excitatory Amino Acid Antagonists</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Excitatory Postsynaptic Potentials</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Genistein</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Glutamic Acid</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
<keyword>Hippocampus</keyword>
<keyword>cytology</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Immunologic Factors</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Interferon-alpha</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Long-Term Potentiation</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>N-Methylaspartate</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Neural Inhibition</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>Neuronal Plasticity</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Pyramidal Cells</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Rats</keyword>
<keyword>Receptors</keyword>
<keyword>GABA-A</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Synapses</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>gamma-Aminobutyric Acid</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
</keywords>
<description></description>
<doi></doi>
<last_update_date>2013-02-27T07:59:09Z</last_update_date>
<creation_date>2013-02-27T07:59:09Z</creation_date>
<publication_year>2000</publication_year>
<publication_month>0</publication_month>
<publication_mday>0</publication_mday>
<lang>eng</lang>
<url>https://dynamicbrain.neuroinf.jp/modules/xoonips/detail.php?item_id=7214</url>
<changelogs>
</changelogs>
<index></index>
</basic>
<detail id="7214" version="1.02">
<authors><author>Mendoza-Fernández V</author><author>Andrew RD</author><author>Barajas-López C</author></authors>
<journal>Brain research</journal>
<volume>885</volume>
<number>1</number>
<page>14-24</page>
<abstract>Interferons (IFN) appear to have various neuromodulatory actions. Here, we characterized the actions of IFN-alpha on the electrophysiological properties of CA1 hippocampal neurons using intracellular recordings. Superfusion of this cytokine did not alter the resting membrane potential, cell input resistance, action potentials, nor GABA-mediated fast synaptic potentials. IFN-alpha inhibited glutamate-mediated excitatory postsynaptic potentials (gEPSPs) and reversed or prevented long-term potentiation (LTP) induced by high-frequency tetanic stimulation. IFN-alpha reduced gEPSP amplitude far below its control value. Only a short-term potentiation (STP) was observed when either IFN-alpha or D-2-amino-5-phosphonovalerato (APV; NMDA receptor antagonist) were present during tetanic stimulation. After this STP in presence of APV, IFN-alpha had no effect on gEPSPs. APV had no effect on LTP when applied after tetanic stimulation and did also not prevent IFN-alpha effect on LTP. Genistein (a tyrosine kinase inhibitor) or heat inactivation prevented IFN-alpha effects. IFN-alpha also decreased the depolarization induced by local application of glutamate but did not modify those induced by NMDA. Similarly, IFN-alpha reversed the potentiation (induced by tetanic stimulation) of glutamate-induced depolarizations. IFN-alpha did not affect long-term depression (LTD) induced by low-frequency tetanic stimulation. In conclusion, IFN-alpha-induced inhibition of LTP is, at least in part, mediated by a postsynaptic effect, by tyrosine kinase activity, and by non-NMDA glutamate receptors. Inhibition of LTP by IFN-alpha unmasks LTD which is induced by the same high-frequency tetanic stimulation.</abstract>
<pubmed_id>11121525</pubmed_id>
</detail>
</item>
