<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item version="1.00">
<basic id="7228">
<itemtype>xnppaper</itemtype>
<titles><title>A NMDA receptor glycine site partial agonist, GLYX-13, simultaneously enhances LTP and reduces LTD at Schaffer collateral-CA1 synapses in hippocampus.</title>
</titles>
<contributor uname='admin'>DBPF Administrator 1(admin)</contributor>
<keywords><keyword>Animals</keyword>
<keyword>Antimetabolites</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Calcium</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Cycloserine</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Data Interpretation</keyword>
<keyword>Statistical</keyword>
<keyword>Excitatory Postsynaptic Potentials</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>Extracellular Space</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>Hippocampus</keyword>
<keyword>cytology</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>Long-Term Potentiation</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>Male</keyword>
<keyword>Memory</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>Neuronal Plasticity</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
<keyword>Oligopeptides</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Rats</keyword>
<keyword>Rats</keyword>
<keyword>Sprague-Dawley</keyword>
<keyword>Receptors</keyword>
<keyword>Glycine</keyword>
<keyword>agonists</keyword>
<keyword>Receptors</keyword>
<keyword>N-Methyl-D-Aspartate</keyword>
<keyword>agonists</keyword>
<keyword>Serine</keyword>
<keyword>pharmacology</keyword>
<keyword>Synapses</keyword>
<keyword>drug effects</keyword>
</keywords>
<description></description>
<doi></doi>
<last_update_date>2013-02-28T01:17:39Z</last_update_date>
<creation_date>2013-02-28T01:17:39Z</creation_date>
<publication_year>2008</publication_year>
<publication_month>0</publication_month>
<publication_mday>0</publication_mday>
<lang>eng</lang>
<url>https://dynamicbrain.neuroinf.jp/modules/xoonips/detail.php?item_id=7228</url>
<changelogs>
</changelogs>
<index></index>
</basic>
<detail id="7228" version="1.02">
<authors><author>Zhang XL</author><author>Sullivan JA</author><author>Moskal JR</author><author>Stanton PK</author></authors>
<journal>Neuropharmacology</journal>
<volume>55</volume>
<number>7</number>
<page>1238-50</page>
<abstract>N-methyl-D-aspartate glutamate receptors (NMDARs) are a key route for Ca2+ influx into neurons important to both activity-dependent synaptic plasticity and, when uncontrolled, triggering events that cause neuronal degeneration and death. Among regulatory binding sites on the NMDAR complex is a glycine binding site, distinct from the glutamate binding site, which must be co-activated for NMDAR channel opening. We developed a novel glycine site partial agonist, GLYX-13, which is both nootropic and neuroprotective in vivo. Here, we assessed the effects of GLYX-13 on long-term synaptic plasticity and NMDAR transmission at Schaffer collateral-CA1 synapses in hippocampal slices in vitro. GLYX-13 simultaneously enhanced the magnitude of long-term potentiation (LTP) of synaptic transmission, while reducing long-term depression (LTD). GLYX-13 reduced NMDA receptor-mediated synaptic currents in CA1 pyramidal neurons evoked by low frequency Schaffer collateral stimulation, but enhanced NMDAR currents during high frequency bursts of activity, and these actions were occluded by a saturating concentration of the glycine site agonist d-serine. Direct two-photon imaging of Schaffer collateral burst-evoked increases in [Ca2+] in individual dendritic spines revealed that GLYX-13 selectively enhanced burst-induced NMDAR-dependent spine Ca2+ influx. Examining the rate of MK-801 block of synaptic versus extrasynaptic NMDAR-gated channels revealed that GLYX-13 selectively enhanced activation of burst-driven extrasynaptic NMDARs, with an action that was blocked by the NR2B-selective NMDAR antagonist ifenprodil. Our data suggest that GLYX-13 may have unique therapeutic potential as a learning and memory enhancer because of its ability to simultaneously enhance LTP and suppress LTD.</abstract>
<pubmed_id>18796308</pubmed_id>
</detail>
</item>
