<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item version="1.00">
<basic id="7252">
<itemtype>xnppaper</itemtype>
<titles><title>Heterogeneity of synaptic plasticity at unitary CA3-CA1 and CA3-CA3 connections in rat hippocampal slice cultures.</title>
</titles>
<contributor uname='admin'>DBPF Administrator 1(admin)</contributor>
<keywords><keyword>Animals</keyword>
<keyword>Culture Techniques</keyword>
<keyword>Excitatory Postsynaptic Potentials</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Hippocampus</keyword>
<keyword>cytology</keyword>
<keyword>metabolism</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Long-Term Potentiation</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Neural Pathways</keyword>
<keyword>metabolism</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Neuronal Plasticity</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Neurons</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Rats</keyword>
<keyword>Receptors</keyword>
<keyword>N-Methyl-D-Aspartate</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Synapses</keyword>
<keyword>physiology</keyword>
<keyword>Time Factors</keyword>
</keywords>
<description></description>
<doi></doi>
<last_update_date>2013-02-28T01:33:37Z</last_update_date>
<creation_date>2013-02-28T01:33:37Z</creation_date>
<publication_year>1999</publication_year>
<publication_month>0</publication_month>
<publication_mday>0</publication_mday>
<lang>eng</lang>
<url>https://dynamicbrain.neuroinf.jp/modules/xoonips/detail.php?item_id=7252</url>
<changelogs>
</changelogs>
<index></index>
</basic>
<detail id="7252" version="1.02">
<authors><author>Debanne D</author><author>Gähwiler BH</author><author>Thompson SM</author></authors>
<journal>The Journal of neuroscience : the official journal of the Society for Neuroscience</journal>
<volume>19</volume>
<number>24</number>
<page>10664-71</page>
<abstract>Long-term potentiation (LTP) of unitary EPSPs, generated by pairs of monosynaptically connected CA3 and CA1 pyramidal cells, was compared with LTP of extracellularly evoked, multi-unitary EPSPs in rat hippocampal slice cultures. LTP was induced by repeated, synchronous pairing of low-frequency presynaptic and postsynaptic activity. Three differences were observed. First, LTP of multi-unitary EPSPs displayed two phases: transient (&lt;5 min) and sustained. Potentiation of unitary EPSPs displayed both phases in 42% of experiments; the remainder showed sustained potentiation only. Unitary EPSPs displaying transient-sustained and only sustained potentiation could be recorded from single postsynaptic cells, indicating that excitatory synapses on a given cell are heterogeneous with respect to short-term plasticity. Second, whereas LTP of multi-unitary EPSPs never resulted in greater than twofold increases in amplitude (mean potentiation of 175% of control), maximal LTP of unitary EPSPs was as great as 13-fold (mean potentiation of 250%). Third, LTP could not be induced in 24% of unitary EPSPs. We provide here the first evidence for the coexistence of potentiatable and nonpotentiatable synapses on individual postsynaptic neurons. Thirty-seven percent of connections not displaying LTP exhibited long-term depression (LTD), suggesting that the connections were already maximally potentiated. In the remaining 63% of these pairs, neither LTP nor LTD could be induced, despite the existence of a pharmacologically identified, NMDA receptor-mediated EPSP component. In conclusion, there is considerable heterogeneity in the amplitude and time course of LTP expression at different synaptic connections. A substantial proportion of apparently nonplastic synapses probably accounts for the weaker potentiation displayed by compound EPSPs.</abstract>
<pubmed_id>10594050</pubmed_id>
</detail>
</item>
