<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item version="1.00">
<basic id="942">
<itemtype>xnppaper</itemtype>
<titles><title>A fundamental oscillatory state of isolated rodent hippocampus.</title>
</titles>
<contributor uname='admin'>DBPF Administrator 1(admin)</contributor>
<keywords></keywords>
<description></description>
<doi></doi>
<last_update_date>2008-07-16T06:25:05Z</last_update_date>
<creation_date>2008-07-16T06:25:05Z</creation_date>
<publication_year>2002</publication_year>
<publication_month>0</publication_month>
<publication_mday>0</publication_mday>
<lang>eng</lang>
<url>https://dynamicbrain.neuroinf.jp/modules/xoonips/detail.php?item_id=942</url>
<changelogs>
</changelogs>
<index></index>
</basic>
<detail id="942" version="1.02">
<authors><author>Wu C</author><author>Shen H</author><author>Luk WP</author><author>Zhang L</author></authors>
<journal>The Journal of physiology</journal>
<volume>540</volume>
<number></number>
<page>509-27</page>
<abstract>Population neuronal rhythms of various frequencies are observed in the rodent hippocampus during distinct behavioural states. However, the question of whether the hippocampus exhibits properties of spontaneous rhythms and population synchrony in isolation has not been definitively answered. To address this, we developed a novel preparation for studying neuronal rhythms in a relatively large hippocampal tissue in vitro. We isolated the whole hippocampus from mice up to 28 days postnatal age, removing the dentate gyrus while preserving the functional CA3-to-CA1 connections. Placing the hippocampal isolate in a perfusion chamber for electrophysiological assessment extracellular recordings from the CA1 revealed rhythmic field potential of 0.5 to&lt;/= 4 Hz that occurred spontaneously and propagated along the ventro-dorsal hippocampal axis. We provide convergent evidence, via measurements of extracellular pH and K(+), recordings of synaptic and intracellular activities and morphological assessments, verifying that these rhythms were not the consequence of hypoxia. Data obtained via simultaneous extracellular and patch clamp recordings suggest that the spontaneous rhythms represent a summation of GABAergic IPSPs originating from pyramidal neurons, which result from synchronous discharges of GABAergic inhibitory interneurons. Similar spontaneous field rhythms were also observed in the hippocampal isolate prepared from young gerbils and rats. Based on these data, we postulate that the spontaneous rhythms represent a fundamental oscillatory state of the hippocampal circuitry isolated from extra-hippocampal inputs.</abstract>
<pubmed_id>11956340</pubmed_id>
</detail>
</item>
